Young Women's Christian Association Photographs 1913-1965
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Young Women's Christian Association Photographs
1913-1965
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections Pullman, WA 99164-5610 USA (509) 335-6691 http://www.wsulibs.wsu.edu/masc/ mascref@wsu.edu
PC 57
1 container 2 linear feet
A collection of black and white photographs from the Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA) at WSU. The bulk of pictures are from Seabeck located near Hood Canal where an annual meeting was held.
Historical Note:
The YWCA of Washington State College was established in 1895. It provided the women of the college a place to worship, held bible classes, locate housing and employment. It also served as a social organization that participated with the YWCA of Washington State College. A popular social event in the 1910's-1930's were the conferences held at Seabeck, (located on Washington's Hood's Canal). Topics at Seabeck focused on issues of the YWCA's and YMCA's of the Pacific Northwest.
During the 1940's the chapter concentrated on global issues, the YWCA had plans to send care packages overseas although the lack of funds prohibited such action. In the 1950's-1960's the organization studied politics and world relations, presenting programs on various subjects, including the war in Vietnam and the Democratic system. In 1969 the YWCA adopted the imperative "the elimination of racism". Programs of the 1970's and the 1980's offered more projects on cultural awareness in the United States.
Membership grew steadily throughout the years, peaking in 1954 with 711 members. In 1972 the membership had dropped to 219 members. The student body provided sole support for the YWCA until 1917 when the University partially funded the secretary's salary. Other assistance was provided by the Helen A. Fuller Endowment Fund established by Fuller in 1929. Presently, the United Way supports over 75% of the YWCA budget.
All of the images are black and white. The bulk of pictures are from Seabeck; those images are arranged in chronological order. There are additional pictures located in the Washington State Publications Office records, PC 1. Oversized materials are listed at the end of the collection, and stoed separately in map cases.
The records of the Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA) were acquired by the Washington State University Libraries in May of 1987.
YMCA (Washington State University, Pullman, Wash.) -- Photographs.; Washington State University -- Societies, etc. -- Photographs.; YWCA (Washington State University, Pullman, Wash.) -- Photographs.; Student activities -- Photographs.; College students -- Religious life -- Photographs.; Washington (State); Colleges and Universities; Student Life; Photographs
- Freshman Rush, 1955 (Folder 1)
- Group Photo, 1947-1948 (Folder 2)
- Group Photo, primarily women, undated (Folder 3)
- Group Photo, primarily men, undated (Folder 4)
- Miscellaneous, 1950 (Folder 5)
- Miscellaneous, undated (Folder 6)
- National Convention, 1922 (Folder 7)
- Nursery School, undated (Folder 8)
- Quartette, The Woods, Officers, 1918-1924 (Folder 9)
- Rooms and Houses, undated (Folder 10)
- 1925-1927 (Map case 11)
- 1954, undated (Folder 12)
- undated (Folder 13)
- undated (Folder 14)
- Smorgasbord, 1955 (Map case 15)
- Speakers - Educational Functions, 1923-1949 (Folder 16)
- 1924-1932 (Map case 12)
- Trucks, undated (Folder 17)
- YWCA Conference, Gearhart OR (rolled in box), 1913 (Folder 18)
- Seabeck, 1923-1949 (Oversized 19)
- Seabeck, 1924-1932 (Oversized 20)
- National Convention, Hot Springs AR, 1922 (Oversized 21)
- Spring, 1950 (Oversized 21)